Finding Aid for the Walter J. Harrelson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Psalms and Spirituality- Scarritt 5/8/93Religious Diversity and Christian Faith (Box 37)
- St. Benedict College, 10/17-18/94 (Box 37)
- St. David’s Church- “Ten Commandments and Human Rights”, Feb. 6, 13, 20, and 27 1994 (Box 37)
- Steve Scott Installation (Harrelson Spoke), 9/27/92 (Box 37)
- Sewanee Theological Review- Issue on Hebrew Bible, December 1993 (Box 37)
- Townsend Article for Sewanee Theological Review (Box 37)
- The Upper Room Disciplines, 1995 (Box 37)
- Wesley Theological Seminary, 10/12-14/92 (Box 37)
- Wild Acres, Aug 3-6, 1992 (Box 37)
- Oct 30, 1992 Biblical Studies Seminar- Texas Christian University- SW Bible Society- “Wisdom” Paper (Box 37)
- Reviews Completed, 1993 and 1994 (Box 37)
- Reviews Completed, 1991-1994 (Box 37)
- Review- Non-Violent Coming of God (Box 37)
- Offprint from Eretz-Israel Arch., Hist., and Geographical Studies Vol 16- H.M. Orlinsky Volume, 1982 (Box 39)
- Walter Harrelson Offprints- An Evaluation of the New Revised Standard Version (Box 39)
- Reviews- Offprints (Box 39)
- Shofar- Vol 3, No.1 Fall, 1984 (Box 39)
- Touchstone- Magazine of the Tennessee Humanities Council- No.10, 1987- The Creation that the Bible Insists Upon- Walter Harrelson (Box 39)
- Biblical Archaeology Review- Nov/Dec 1986 Vol XII No 6- What Is A Good Bible Dictionary?- WH (Box 39)
- New Disciples Fall 1986- The Ten Commandments in Jewish and Christian History- WH (Box 39)
- Union Sem. Qtly Review Vol 42 Nos. 1 and 2, 1988- Eschatology and Ethics in the Hebrew Bible- WH (Box 39)
- The New American Bible- WH (Box 39)
- The Messianic Hope- WH (Box 39)
- Ency. Of Religion in the South- Theological Education –WH (Box 39)
- Messianic Expectations at the Time of Jesus- WH- SLJT, Dec 1988, Vol XXXII, No.1 (Box 39)
- A Protestant Looks at Catholic Biblical Scholarship- WH- The Biblical Heritage in Modern Catholic Scholarship (Box 39)
- Karl Barth on the Decalogue- WH- Studies in Religion 6/3/, 1976-77 (Box 39)
- The Qumran Community’s Life, Faith and Hopes- WH- Quarterly Review Spring, 1994 (Box 39)
- The Ten Commandments and Human Rights- WH- The Journal of Intergroup Relations Vol. XVII, No. 4 (Box 39)
- The Biblical Understanding of Spirituality- WH- The Ecumenical Review Vol. XV, No.3, April 1963 (Box 39)
- Patient Love in the Testament of Joseph- WH- Perspectives in Religious Studies 1977, 4-13 (Box 39)
- Wisdom Hidden and Revealed According to Baruch- WH- Priests, Prophets and Scribes, Journal for the Old Testament Supplement Series 149 (Box 39)
- Famine in the Perspective of Biblical Judgments and Promises- WH- Soundings, Spr. 1976 Vol LIX, No 1 (Box 39)
- Thoughts on Ecumenism- WH-Occ. Papers Inst. For Ecumenism and Cultural Research No. 22, April 1984 (Box 39)
- The Religion of Ancient Israel- WH- Listening: Journal of Religion and Culture- Winter, 1984 (Box 39)
- Christian Misreadings of Basic Themes in the Hebrew Scriptures- WH-Quarterly Review Vol 2 No.2, 1982 (Box 39)
- Prophetic Eschatological Visions and the Kingdom of God- WH- Quest for the Kingdom of God: Studies in Honor of George E. Mendenhall. (Box 39)
- Wisdom and Pastoral Theology-WH_ Andover Newton Quarterly, Sept. 1966 (Box 39)
- A Meditation on the Wrath of God: Psalm 90- WH (Box 39)
- Guidance in the Wilderness: The Theology of Numbers- WH- Interpretation: J. of Bible and Theology Vol. XIII, 1959 (Box 39)
- Creation- WH- The Christian Scholar (Box 39)
- On God’s Care for the Earth- Psalm 104- WH- Currents in Theology and Mission, Vol. 2 No1, Feb. 1975 (Box 39)
- The Significance of “Last Words” for Intertestamental Ethics- WH- Essays in Old Testament Ethics (Box 39)
- Ezra Among the Wicked in 2 Esdras 3-10- WH-The Divine Helmsman (Box 39)
- Celebration of the Feast of Booths “According to Zech xiv 16-21-WH- Religions in Antiquity, 1968 (Box 39)
- The New Revised Standard Version Bible I- WH-Prism 6.1 Spring, 1991 (Box 39)
- National Purpose and Ancient Vision- WH- The Christian Century, June 29, 1960 (Box 39)
- God’s Sovereignty and Man’s Dominion- WH- The Pulpit: A J. of Contemporary Preaching Vol XXXI,No., 2 Feb 1960 (Box 39)
- The CRS in Retrospect and Prospect-WH- Bulletin of the The Council on the Study of Religion Vol 16 No., 2 Apr 1985 (Box 39)
- Reflection on the Value for Biblical Scholars of the New Encyclopedia of Religion-WH- Bulletin of the The Council on the Study of Religion Vol 17 No2, April 1988 (Box 39)
- Worship-WH- Encyclopedia Britannica, 1974 (Box 39)
- The Limited Task of Old Testament Theology-WH (Box 39)
- On God’s Knowledge of the Self- Psalm 139-WH (Box 39)
- Review- When Prophesy Failed: Cognitive Dissonance in the Prophetic Traditions of the Old Testament by Robert P. Carroll-WH- Zygon Vol 16 no 4, Dec 1981 (Box 39)
- Death and Victory in 1 Corinthians 15:51-57: The Transformation of a Prophetic Theme- WH- Faith and History: Essays in Honor of Paul W. Meyer (Box 39)
- Isaiah 35 in Recent Research and Translation-WH-Language, Theology and The Bible: Essays in Honour of James Barr (Box 39)
- The Vatican Accord: Is a Christian Reassessment of Israel Likely?- A Symposium- WH- Midstream, January 1995 (Box 39)
- Review- Cristofania: Nove tesi by Raimundo Panikkar- WH- J. of Ecumenical Studies Vol. 33, no. 3 Summer, 1996 (Box 39)
- Review- The Anchor Bible Dictionary: An Encyclopedia of the Ancient Near Eastern World-JBL 113/2, 1994 (Box 39)
- The Ten Commandments- WH- Growing Christians Series, 1988 (Box 39)
- Review- Theologians Under Hitler: Gerhard Kittel, Paul Althaus, and Emanuel Hirsch, - By Robert P.Ericksen-WH- Theology Today, April 1986 (Box 39)
- Eschatology and Ethics in the Hebrew Bible-WH-Union Seminary Quarterly Review Vol 42 No 1&2, 1988 (Box 39)
- Inclusive Language in the New Revised Standard Version-WH- Princeton Seminary Bulletin Vol XI No 3, 1990 (Box 39)
- About to be Born-WH- Andover Newton Quarterly November 1970 Vol 11, No 2 (Box 39)
- The Origin of Language according to the Bible-WH- Studies in Language Origins, Vol 2, 1991 (Box 39)
- Review- Theology of the Old Testament, Vol I by Walther Eichrodt and A Thousand Years and a Day by Claus Westermann- WH- Student World- No. 4, 1962 (Box 39)
- Recent Discoveries and Bible Translation-WH- Religious Eduction Vol. 85, No. 2, Spring, 1990 (Box 39)
- Famine in the Perspective of Biblical Judgments and Promises-WH- Soundings Vol. LXI No.1, Spring, 1976 (Box 39)
- Guilt and Rites of Purification Related to the Fall of Jerusalem in 587 B.C.-WH- Numen International Review for the History of Religions Vol. XV, Fasc. 3, November 1968 (Box 39)
- Review- The Hebrew Bible- A Socio-Literary Introduction by Norman K. Gottwald-WH- Union Seminary Quarterly Review VolXLI No. 1, 1986 (Box 39)
- Walter Harrelson: Festschrift on, September 21, 1989 (Box 39)
- Cassette- Walter Harrelson- Faith Seeking Knowledge, 9/18/87 (Box 39)
- Microfilm Reel- Ethiopian Manuscript (Box 39)